

John R. Mahoney

• PROFILE •

I'm a rad dad who endeavors to make the world a fizzier place. A physicist by training and jazz saxophonist by night, I approach the world with both an analytic mind and a the desire for a deep pocket.

• PROGRAMMING •

Python: np, sp, mpl, pd GUI / interactive git, LATEX, beamer, tikz ipython, Jupyter, VS Code MATLAB Mac OS, UNIX

• INTERPERSONAL •

Excellent listener Flexible and creative Work well in close-knit teams Independent worker Thoughtful mentor Value clear communication

• PROJECTS •

Python & Physics course Burning Invariant Manifolds CMPy contributor Simpson's Paradox timesquare this resumè

• INTERESTS •

jazz saxophone and piano soccer, tennis, and hiking cooking and eating delicious food!

mohnjahoney@gmail.com (530) 601-0524 mohnjahoney.github.io





• COMMUNICATION SKILLS •

Written: Wrote and co-authored over 25 papers published in high quality journals

> (PRL, PRX, PRA, PRE, CHAOS, J. Stat Phys.). Edited multiple articles for colleagues. Refereed for several journals. Read about: prediction, react-

ing fluids, quantum information.

Verbal: Designed and delivered over 35 talks and posters including: Quantum

> Info Workshop at Nanyang Technical University, Singapore; Conference on Complex Systems, Amsterdam; CHAOS15 at Henri Poincaré Institute, Paris; Oberwolfach, Germany (awarded "best poster"); International Con-

ference on Flow Dynamics, Sendai, Japan

Graphical: Value design and aesthetics in communication. I seek to balance precision

and depth with clarity and impact. One significant output of my research on reacting flows is the graphical presentation of an augmented flow topology. My research in information theory was often facilitated by Venn diagrams, a technique I helped to incorporate in my research group. Sometimes, as with my study on self-propelled agents, the result is as much art as it is science. Look at: topology of reacting flows, info diagram, Poincaré

• ANALYTIC SKILLS •

Connected my work on reacting fluids to several existing fields: invariant Research:

> manifolds, finite-time Lyapunov exponents, advection-reaction-diffusion equation, catastrophe theory, path planning in autonomous vehicles, differ-

ential geometry.

Critical Think-

Reframed an assumption in the literature to create a fruitful research av-

enue - crypticity and cryptic order.

ing: Data:

Created Python pipeline for data on diabetes patients: clean, process, ana-

lyze (multiple pair lagged regression), visualize.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Fall 2020 Math Specialist: UC Davis

Course Designer and Instructor: UC Davis Summer 2020

Oct 2019 Math Lecturer: Napa Valley College

Spring 2019 Physics Lecturer: UC Davis Fall 2018 Math Lecturer: CSU Maritime

2017-2018 Consultant: Dept. Biomedical Informatics, Columbia University

Fall 2017 Spring 2018, Math Lecturer: UC Davis

2015-2017 Project Scientist: UC Davis 2010-2015 Postdoctoral Scholar: UC Merced

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in Physics, UC, Davis with James P. Crutchfield

B.S. in Physics and Mathematics, CSU, Chico

attended Williams College for Physics, Mathematics and Music